erlibird.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy - Erli Bird

## Erli Bird Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is a portion of the Erli Bird Terms of Usage Agreement, and is included to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you share through the website. 

We respect your right to privacy and will not give your personal information to third parties.

### Communication Through Email

We allow you to get on our email list by providing your email address or using our join/login system to login with various third-party credentials.

If you don't want to hear from us, please opt-out from our emails on the bottom of the email. If for some reason this does not work or you would rather contact us directly, please email us at team@erlibird.com and we will promptly remove you from our list.

By default, we will send you approximately one or two emails a week related to new startups and products that we feature.

Users that have requested access to Erli Bird but have not yet been granted access will not be sent recurring weekly emails.

We may send you service announcements or notifications.

### When Your Information is Shared

As important function of Erli Bird is to allow users to locate startups and communicate with founders. As such, an integral part of the service is facilitating communication by sharing the information that you make available through your profile (either directly, or by logging in through a social networking service). If you sign up and "Claim Your Spot" for a Startup incentive, you grant us the right to share your personal information with the Startup. This helps facilitate delivery of the incentive and communication between you and the startup founders. Startups must agree not to abuse your personal information prior to being listed on Erli Bird.

We use a third-party login system from Janrain called Engage in order to allow you to login using your credentials from various popular third party websites. As the provider of these systems, your login and social profile data is first accessed and processed by Janrain and then sent to Erli Bird.

We may provide your information to third parties in certain situations:

  * To comply with a legal request, such as a search warrant, court order, or subpoena. In such circumstances, we limit disclosure until we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary, or that it meets applicable legal standards.
  * When we believe it is necessary to prevent fraud or other suspected illegal activities.
  * When we believe it is required to protect our interests, rights, reputation or property, or those of our users, members, affiliates, or partners.
  * We may provide your information in aggregate, without personally identifying you, to third parties for market research, analyzing user behavior, or for other business or marketing analysis.
  * We may provide your personal information to third party service providers to help provide the services of the Erli Bird Website. We may use third parties to provide our underlying data network, host our web servers, provide our storage, deliver our email, process our payments, or provide our marketing material or advertisements. Through the performance of these business activities, our service providers may have access to your personal information.
  * Erli Bird reserves the right to transfer your user information to a successor if interest in ownership of all or substantially all of Erli Bird were to change.

### Sharing Content Publicly

Certain areas of the site allow you to share content publicy. Any information (including personally identifiable information) that you share in public areas may be viewed, stored, or otherwise used by other users. You should think carefully about what information you choose to disclose publicly.

### Technology

We automatically collect certain information as you browse the Website. We collect your IP address, general location, browser type, browser software version, and other information about the device used to browse our Website and how you connect to and use our Website. We also use third party platforms to help us analyze our traffic and usage patterns at an aggregate level in order to administer and improve our Website and services.

Erli Bird works with certain third party software providers in order to provide the Website, and sections of the Website may include code or scripts from third parties. These third party software providers may have access to certain personal information collected through the Website. Google is used to provide analytics data to Erli Bird, and both Google and Erli Bird will have access to your anonymous traffic data.

Our Website, email systems, and advertisements make use of "cookies" and related technologies such as web beacons. "Cookies" are small files that are stored on your local hard drive that allow the Website to operate and help us improve the service. For example, we use cookies to allow users to log in and log out of Erli Bird and maintain data associated with each user session. We also use cookies to collect and track information about how you use our site, including what pages you visit, how long you stay on each page, and your navigation patterns. We use web beacons in email and advertisements to help us measure the effectiveness of our communications, prevent spam and fraud, and track whether or not a certain email has been opened. Long term persistent cookies are used to allow users to revisit our website without logging in every time.

When you login to our site using Facebook or otherwise link your account with Facebook or another social networking service, you permit Erli Bird to access, collect, and indefintely store and use the information made available to us through the social networking site related to your account and/or your friends accounts. The information you allow Erli Bird to access is dependent on your privacy settings at the applicable third party site and made available to Erli Bird upon clicking "accept", "allow" or other similar term.

### Security

We will take appropriate industry-standard precautions to protect your information and prevent the access, misuse or loss of your data. Your information is stored behind physical and software firewalls, and access is only permitted to authenticated sessions initiated on Erli Bird servers. The network on which Erli Bird hardware and software resides provides protection for Denial of Service Attacks, Man in the Middle Attacks, IP Spoofing, and Packet Sniffing. The data centers used to host Erli Bird servers are protected by physical access control, video surveillance, and intrusion detection systems.

However, no amount of physical or virtual security is impenetrable. We try hard to keep your data private and secure, but we cannot guarantee privacy or security. Erli Bird has no control over the actions of other users with whom you may share your information. Furthermore, the security and stability of the Erli Bird Website is reliant on hardware and software which can fail and other factors that could potentially compromise your information, such as unauthorized user access or the actions of hackers. All sharing of personal and Project information through the Erli Bird Website is done at your own risk.

### Contacting Us

Please contact Erli Bird with any questions, comments, or to report a violation of the Privacy Policy: Michael Siegler, mike@erlibird.com, 1960 N. Lincoln Park West, 2412, Chicago, IL 60614.
